Yufenyuy Veyeh Didier

A detailed Software Engineer with over six years of professional experience in full stack web development and information technology. Highly familiar with QA, Software System Analysis, Computational Thinking, Testing and TDD, VCS, DBMS, DevOps, and progressive frameworks such as VueJS.

Bangue, Douala Littoral, Cameroon (00237) 675 007 995 tenshnova@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Tenshnova, Cameroon — Proj Dev Manager & Lead SE

January 2021 - Present

Help clients to automate their activities and solve complex problems with easy solutions.

Recently helped a local bank (unicsgroup) to rethink and redesign their website which will give them more visibility and credibility.

Equally working on some interesting projects that can be seen here.

Working with a team on a few innovative projects which are under an NDA.

Synepsys, Cameroon — Software Application Developer

May 2018 - January 2021

Built the front-end of an inventory management system for a client of the company with bootstrap 3.

Worked on a school management application "Kunea" using the Django framework, JQuery, PostgreSQL, and Python too, while equally writing unit tests for every implementation I made since we were using a TDD approach in the company.

Worked on the front end of an advanced version of Kunea making use of VueJS, Vuex, NodeJS, JSON, and Material Design.

As of now, the Kunea project is still under development and is awaiting its launch. We couldn't meet its deadline due to the redesign of the architecture and interfaces which changed several technical aspects of the project. Nevertheless, I can't currently tell how far the project has gone by now given that I no longer work at Synepsys since the end of January.

ECAM-Patronat, Cameroon — Lead Software Engineer

December 2017 - May 2018

Maintained and executed administrative tasks on the company's website. Did basic graphic design tasks. Updated, enhanced, and maintained a voting web

SKILLS

Office Space Design and
Economy
Software Analysis & QA
Communication & Sales
Coding and Testing
Software Project Management
Ability to be Hybrid
Can work with pressure

CODING SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, SQL, Python, Java, Ruby, Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, Flutter, VueJS, ReactJS, JSON, Ionic, Angular, Gulp, Sass, Webpack, Jest, Typescript.

MEMBERSHIPS

GitHub Developer Program (Member)

Tiens Tianshi Group (Distributor)

Ask Ubuntu Community & Launchpad (Contributor)

International Youth Fellowship (IYF - Member)

Good News Medical Volunteers (Volunteer)

application that was already broken thus permitting its use in a startup challenge in Douala, Cameroon.

Designed, coordinated, implemented, and tested a candidate application voting platform with OOP principles, later used in over three African countries with positive feedback.

Shafrique, Cameroon — Software Engineer

June 2017 - December 2017

Performed Software Engineering Tasks. (Agile Project Management, Database Administration, Graphic Design, Software Analysis, Software Design, Software Development, Software Integration, Software Testing, Support)

Designed and developed a web chat module for the company's main platform.

Develop a module to transform and export data from one format to another which eliminated the required manual approach, favored task automation thus improving efficiency.

Designed and developed a website for two top clients of the company in a brief delay which permitted the company to see an increase in profit with a very short time span as compared to before.

Worked in a team to build a little python bot to scrape the web and get vital and useful information for a web app (Social media platform) which was used to grab required information and eased our work on the development and maintenance of the said platform.

IT-Kamer Ltd, Cameroon — Junior Software Engineer

April 2015 - January 2017

Worked with IT-Kamer as a Junior Software Engineer performing tasks in the following domains: Software Analysis, Software Design, Software Development, Software Integration, Software Testing, Support, IT Training, and hugely focused on Web Technologies.

Worked in a team to build a point of sale that also had an inventory management system and could be integrated into the <u>iDempiere ERP</u> System. This was initially a fork of uniCenta oPOS which we later added our own designed features.

Created awareness and marketed this product. Successfully installed and provided technical assistance to a Lounge (among other places) in Limbe, Cameroun while leading a team of four developers, one designer, and two marketers. Deployed and tested Point Of Sales - ERP Software Integrations.

Did Search Engine Optimization for some websites such as "wandaapos.com - at the time, ..." and created social media awareness.

Implemented Java Reporting with Jasper Report for an Open Source POS,

LANGUAGES

English, French, Nso, Korean(Basic)

HOBBIES

Painting, Reading, Playing Pool, Cuisine and Gardening.

WandaPOS. This enhanced the amount of statistical data that could be pulled from the system.

Implemented Java DB Connection, Data Entry and DB Administration, which ameliorated the functionality of applications making use of this by an efficiency of over 80%.

Trained apprentices in Software Engineering Courses as an Assistant in the School of Media Design and Information Technology, a branch of the LUC, Buea.

EDUCATION

Landmark University College, Buea — B.Eng

October 2014 - December 2018

Bachelor of Engineering - Industrial Software Engineering

PROJECTS

Posta — An Auto content migration system

Posta is a personal project which comprises a platform to aid bloggers automatically migrate content from google docs to WordPress after they must have collaborated on docs. I currently and occasionally work on this.

Payment Terminal — An Android Payment Terminal

Worked on a Payment Terminal on android application, conceiving its views and functionalities, and seeing through the project to deployment. Delivered the required product on budget and time thereby establishing good customer relationship and satisfaction between the client and the company.

Pio — An online voting platform

An online digital voting platform with an admin, jury, and contestant sections, that was successfully used for the PMExchange Challenge in Douala, Cameroon, and over one hundred contestants were voted upon by the jury.

A few issues (bugs) but were fixed and managed within the short given time.

ice-cookies — A cookie consent plugin

A light, fast, optimal, and customizable cookie consent plugin built with typescript and sass, bundled with gulp, and distributed through packaged html, css, and javascript.

consoleprevent.js — A javascript module

A minimal javascript module to prevent a web user from accessing the console built with jquery.

<u>csv-json-py</u> — A python package

A minimal light tool to convert csv to json and vice-versa in python.

Other Projects

Other minor projects can be found in this link.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- 1. Managed a team of 9 young developers which led to a successful accomplishment of a company project.
- 2. Conceived and implemented a web design and development project in a software company, and that secured a 2 millions fcfa deal.
- 3. Presented to an audience of 200+ in a company business trip, which encouraged the company brand and generated a good ROI.
- Published several open source code, modules, and node packages useful for easing software development.
- 5. Arctic Code Vault Contributor on Github.

HONORS & AWARDS

- 1st place, Best student, Industrial Software Engineering, Landmark University College, Buea, 2015, which led to being offered a junior software engineer's position at IT-Kamer Ltd.
- Recognition for outstanding project accomplishments due to detail-oriented design and implementation skills, LUC, Buea.
- 3. Scholarship, Landmark University College, School of Media Design and Information Technology, 2014 2018.
- 4. Recognition for outstanding implementation and documentation of Search Engine Optimization of the WandaPOS website.
- Best blog article in [Object-Oriented Analysis and Design +
 Object-Oriented Programming] classroom projects, Landmark
 University College, School of Media Design and Information
 Technology.

REFERENCES

Mme Ndi Britha Lea, Software Engineer, Chair & Co-Founder, Tenshnova. (leadelve@gmail.com)

Mr Essame Christian Richard, CEO & Founder, Kamer Startup Hub / Contractor, ECAM Patronat. (essamechristian@gmail.com)